Mss.Ms.Coll.95 Mss.Ms.Coll.95
American Philosophical Society
- Series II. Research Subjects (Box 19-85)
  - Other Languages and Cultures of the Americas (Box 78-82)
    - South America (Box 79-81)
      - Quecha (Box 80-81)
        - Texts, n.d.; 13 pages (Box 81)
          Quechua with English translations, many duplicate copies, possibly material prepared for teaching.
        - Los Dialectos Quechuas, 1964; 1 item; Torero, A. (Box 81)
          Offprint from Anales Cientificos de la Universidad Agraria, Vol. II, No. 4, Lima, Peru.
        - Vocabulary and Sentences, ca. 140 pages (Box 81)
          Handwritten ms-phonemic inventory with examples, Quechua vocabulary with English glosses, Quechua sentences with English translations and some analysis.
        - Word Lists, Cuzco, n.d.; 21 pages (Box 81)
          Cuzco-English (Escobar) and English-Cuzco word lists possibly for teaching. Includes multilith masters for Cuzco-English list.
        - Word Lists, Unidentified Dialect, n.d.; 14 pages (Box 81)
          English-Quechua and Quechua-English word lists.
      - Absolute Chronology in the Andean Area, 1945; 2 items; Rowe, John Howland, 1918-2004 (Box 81)
        Photocopy of article from American Antiquity, Vol. 3; includes hand drawn chart of 16th Century Spanish genealogy of Hidalgo families.
      - South American Language Classification Project, 1952, n.d.; 25 pages; Rowe, John Howland, 1918-2004 (Box 81)
        Description of information desired and vocabulary list to be collected for preliminary comparison and classification. Includes syllabus for Anthropology 105B and "Short Inca Bibliography."
      - Class Structure Draft, n.d.; 12 pages; [Schaedel, Richard P.] (Box 81)
        Typed manuscript with discussion of Inca Empire, Chimu confederacy, etc. From folder: "Manuscripts of R. Schaedel"
      - El obispo D. Baltazar Jaime Martinez Companon y la etnologia del Peru a fines del siglo XVIII, n.d.; 13 pages; [Schaedel, Richard P.] (Box 81)
        Typed manuscript. From folder: "Manuscripts of R. Schaedel"
      - Major Ceremonial and Population Centers in Northern Peru, ca. 50 pages; Schaedel, Richard P. (Box 81)
        Typed draft manuscript. From folder: "Manuscripts of R. Schaedel"
      - Nuevos discrubrimientos de relieves ornamentales en Chan Chan, n.d.; 8 pages; [Schaedel, Richard P.] (Box 81)
        Carbon of typed manuscript. From folder: "Manuscripts of R. Schaedel"
      - Report on a Study Conducted in Northern Chile, 39 pages; Schaedel, Richard P. (Box 81)
        Typed manuscript. regarding ecological adaptation by inhabitants, etc. From folder: "Manuscripts of R. Schaedel"
      - Review of The Art of Ancient Peru, n.d.; 5 pages; Schaedel, Richard P. (Box 81)
      - Review of Cultural Stratigraphy in the Viru Valley, Northern Peru: The Formative and Florescent Epochs, 9 pages; [Schaedel, Richard P.] (Box 81)
      - Review of Culturas Precolombiana de Chile, n.d.; 3 pages; Schaedel, Richard P. (Box 81)
      - Terena, n.d.; 2 folders (Box 81)
        Vocabulary, texts, notes, etc.
      - Terena and Guarani Wire Recordings Tables of Contents, Circa 1950; 1 item (Box 81)
        Table of Contents to wire recording made in Mato Grosso, Brazil. Languages on recording are Terena, Guarani, Swedish, Portuguese, and English.
      - Tupy-Tembe Grammar, n.d.; 1 item (Box 81)
        Two versions of a short grammar compiled by Horace H. Banner, Unevangelized Field Mission-introduction and lessons.
      - Umotina, n.d.; 6 pages (Box 81)
        Vocabulary given by consultant Cupo Donepo, with Portuguese glosses.
      - Unidentified, n.d.; 128 slips (Box 81)
        [Probably Brazil]. Vocabulary with Portuguese and some English glosses.
      - Venezuelan Languages, 1946, n.d.; 3 items (Box 81)
        Guaika vocabulary collected by J. M. Cruxent; unidentified notes; Julio Febres Cordero, "Un Vocabulario Caribe del Oriente Venezolano," Publicaciones del Ministerio de Educacion Nacional, Caracas. Includes 2 pencil sketches, Inca figure, map of Venezuela.
      - Maya-Bororo-Ge Comparisons, n.d.; 1 p; [Ventur, Pierre] (Box 81)
        List of 10 items from basic vocabulary.
      - Waimari, 1991-1993, n.d.; 6 items (Box 81)
        A variety of articles and manuscripts including: pages 226-231 of Mason's South American Indians, B. A. E. Bulletin 143, Vol. 6; "A Brazilian Tribe Escapes Extinction," World Development, March 1991; "A Experiencia Educacional do Subprograma de Educacao do Programa Waimiri-Atroari de 1988 a 1991" (typed manuscript and letter); letter regarding positions available as "ecotravel" guides in the Amazon region; "Dicionario Bilingue Waimiri-Atroari/Portugues, Portugues/Waimiri-Atroari" (typed manuscript); "Ki'nja Ika Historias Waimiri-Atroari" (typed manuscript). Includes 13 photomechanical prints of native settlements, individual and group portraits, preparing bread, hunting.
      - A Dictionary of Ge: A Linguistic Family of South America, n.d.; ca. 100 pages; Wilbert, Johannes (Box 81)
        Carbon of typed manuscript, alphabetical by English, giving vocabulary items in various languages. From folder: "'Ge' Linguistic Family of South America and Bororo Comparisons."
      - Lexico-Statistic Dating List of "Ge", n.d.; ca. 50 pages; Wilbert, Johannes (Box 81)
        A typed manuscript using vocabulary from various languages. Also includes typed manuscript entitled "Ge-Linguistic Family of South America." From folder: "'Ge' Linguistic Family of South America and Bororo Comparisons."
      - Wintukwa (Chibchan) Kinship Terms, n.d.; 8 pages (Box 81)
        Wintukwa (Chibchan) (also known as Arhuaka) kinship terms-handwritten compilation.
      - The Morphology and Syntax of Kechua, 33 pages; Yokoyama [Lounsbury], Masako (Box 81)
        Typed documents with handwritten comments probably by FGL.
      - Preliminary Analysis of Suffixes in Kechua, 1948; 27 pages; Yokoyama [Lounsbury], Masako (Box 81)
        Typed manuscript with handwritten note probably by FGL. Includes bibliography and weekly reading list for Linguistics 101a and handwritten notes on Quechua morphology.
      - Yunga, n.d.; 40 pages (Box 81)
        Multilith masters and uncut slips of incomplete religious texts; list of typewriter substitutions for Middendorf's symbols in Yunga. Languages used-Yunga, Spanish, and German.
      - El Juego de los Ayllus y el Amaru, n.d.; 1 item; Zuidema, R. Tom, (Reiner Tom), 1927- (Box 81)
        Offprint from Societe des Americanistes publication.
      - Meaning in Nazca Art: Iconographic relationships between Inca-, Huari-, and Nazca cultures in Southern Peru, 1 item; Zuidema, R. Tom, (Reiner Tom), 1927- (Box 81)
        Offprint from unidentified publication. Includes 11 photomechanical prints of pottery.
    - Dominican Creole, Taylor, Douglas (Box 82)
    - Unidentified Languages (Box 82)
      - Myth Text, 3.0 folders (Box 82)
      - Sentences (Box 82)
      - Text, Typescript of texts and one page of translated elicitations. Place names in the translated sentences are towns in Burma. (Box 82)
      - Vocabulary, 2.0 folders (Box 82)
  - Salish (Box 82-83)
    - Plateau Interior Salishan: Historical Linguistics and Dialect Geography, Kinkade, M. Dale (Marvin Dale), 1933- (Box 82)
    - Kalispel Field Notes, 1936, 3.0 folders; Smith, Allan H., (Allan Hathorn), 1913-1999 (Box 82)
    - Kalispel Field Notes, 1937, 5.0 folders; Smith, Allan H., (Allan Hathorn), 1913-1999 (Box 83)
    - Kalispel Field Notes, 1938, 3.0 folders; Smith, Allan H., (Allan Hathorn), 1913-1999 (Box 83)
    - Snowshoe Tracing (left shoe), Smith, Allan H., (Allan Hathorn), 1913-1999 (Box 83)
  - Uto-Aztecan (Box 84-85)
    - Uto-Aztecan Classification and Sound Shifts, 2 pages; Anonymous (Box 84)
      Tree chart of languages and table of sound changes from Proto-Uto-Aztecan to various languages.
    - Northern Ute Field Notes, 1936; ca. 400 pages; 2 folders; Cooke, Anne M., (Anne M. Smith), 1900-1981 (Box 84)
      Carbon of typed manuscript. Probably from 1936 and 1937 as reported in letters to Edward Sapir and Leslie Spier.
    - Fieldnotes [from Puebla, Mexico], 1965; 1 item; Grady, John M. (Box 84)
      Typed manuscript. of Nahua field notes from Puebla, Mexico.
    - Fieldnotes regarding Uintah, 1935-1937; ca. 800 pages; 5 folders; La Barre, Weston, 1911-1996 (Box 84)
      Myth and ethnographic texts in English-carbon of typed manuscripts. Includes description of social organization, kinship, customs, tools, etc.
    - Noun Classes and Folk Taxonomy in Papago (Tohono O'odham), 1961; 23 pages; Mathiot, Madeleine, 1927- (Box 85)
      Paper read at the annual meeting of the Southwestern Anthropological Association and submitted for publication in the American Anthropologist.
    - Proposal for a Study of Method in Language and Culture Research, 21 pages; Mathiot, Madeleine, 1927- (Box 85)
      Mimeo of typed document regarding a study of Papago (Tohono O'odham).
    - The Numic Languages, 1972, n.d.; 36 pages; Miller, Wick R. (Box 85)
      Draft of WRM's article for HNAI, correspondence.
    - Notes on Nahuatl, n.d.; 20 pages (Box 85)
      FGL's notes and photocopies from dictionaries.
    - Notes on Uto-Aztecan Languages, 1970, n.d.; 60 pages (Box 85)
      Photocopies of selected pages from numerous sources
    - Kawaiisu Ethnographic Material, 1937; ca. 150 pages; Zigmond, Maurice L. (Box 85)
      Typed manuscript. Probably from 1937 field work as reported in letter to Leslie Spier.
    - Kawaiisu Field Notes, 1936; ca. 125 pages; Zigmond, Maurice L. (Box 85)
      Typed manuscript. From 1936 field work.
- Series III. Teaching Notes (Box 85-92)
  - An Oneida Teaching Grammar, Abbott, Clifford (Box 85)
  - Acoustic Phonetics (Box 85)
  - An Application of Contingency Tables as an Aid to Maya Hieroglyph Decipherment, Adams, Ed, III (Box 85)
  - Alumni Seminar: "Survival of American Indian Culture" (Box 85)
  - Anthropology 42 and 103 (Box 85)
  - Anthropology 42b - Language and Culture (Box 85)
  - Anthropology 43 and 116 Course Notes (Box 85)
  - Anthropology 104a. Prehistoric Archaeology: Old World (I. B. Rouse), 2.0 folders (Box 85)
  - Anthropology 109 - Peoples of Oceania (Howells) (Box 85)
  - Anthropology 116 a/b - Kinship Outline (Box 86)
  - Anthropology 116b - The Analysis of Kinship Systems, 1959-1961 (Box 86)
  - Anthropology 116b - Student Work (Box 86)
  - Anthropology 142 - Introduction to Racial History (Howells) (Box 86)
  - Ara Dictionary (Box 86)
    From Edward Calnet, University of Rochester
  - [Asia and Middle East - Anthropological Notes] (Box 86)
  - Le Vocabulaire des institutions indo-europeennes, Benveniste, Emile, 1902-1976 (Box 86)
  - Definition of a Language, Bloch, Bernard, 1907-1965 (Box 86)
  - Cantonese (Box 86)
  - An Application of the Lexico-statistc dating method to four of the Slavic Languages, Chew, John (Box 86)
  - Comparative Exercise - Quecha - Aymara (Box 86)
  - Comparative Exercise - Spanish - Portugese (Box 86)
  - Conceptual Framework for Semiotic (especially Linguistics and Semantics) (Box 86)
  - Domingo de Ara: Ars Tzeldaica (Box 86)
  - Economics (Box 86)
  - Ethnology (Box 86)
  - Ezra Stiles Seminar: Claude Levi-Strauss (Box 86)
  - Glottochronology Rate Problems (Box 86)
  - Ritual and Community Boundaries among the Guajiro, Goulet, Jean-Guy (Box 86)
  - Grammar (Box 86)
  - Indo-European Kinship (Box 87)
  - Interrogative Lists (General. Kinship) (Box 87)
  - Introduction to the Study of Systems of Kinship (Projected book c. 1960) (Box 87)
  - Irish (Box 87)
  - Iroquois Syntax (Mohawk, Oneida) (Box 87)
  - On Phonemes, Jones, Daniel (Box 87)
  - Michigan, 1947, Joos, Martin (Box 87)
  - Key to Morgan. On Pawnee (Box 87)
  - Kinship Teaching Notes (Box 87)
  - Kiwai (Box 87)
  - Language and Culture Course, 4.0 folders (Box 87)
  - Language and Culture - Comparative Linguistics (Box 87)
  - Language and Culture - History of Languages (Box 87)
  - Language and Culture - Hoijer (Box 87)
  - Language and Culture - Linguistic Classification of North and Middle America (Box 87)
  - Language and Culture - Notes (Box 87)
  - Language and Culture - Poetry (Box 87)
  - Language and Culture - Semantics (Box 87)
  - Language Typology - Introduction (Box 87)
  - Language Typology - Miscellaneous (Box 87)
  - Language Typology - Qabardian (Box 88)
  - Language Typology - Tagolog (Box 88)
  - Latin (Box 88)
  - Latin Data Sheets. Rochester, April 1970. (Last version) (Box 88)
  - Latin Lecture - Seattle Version (Box 88)
  - Latin: Miscellaneous (Box 88)
  - Latin Thesaurus Entries (Box 88)
  - Latin: Thesaurus Linguae Latinae (Box 88)
  - Kinship Data and Notes, Levak, Zarko David, 1934- (Box 88)
  - Lexicostatistical Comparisons (Box 88)
  - Linguistics, 3.0 folders (Box 88)
  - Linguistics 109A - Term Papers (Box 89)
  - Lotz. Multiliths (Box 89)
  - On the Meanings of the Latin Kinship Terms. Yale. March 1965, Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 89)
  - On a Theory of the Meanings of the Latin Kinship Terms. UCLA. 1964, Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 89)
  - The Structure of the Latin Kinship System and its Relation to Roman Social Organization, Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 89)
  - The Varieties of Meaning and Assorted Notes, Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 89)
  - Matrilateral Cross-Cousin Marriage Comparative Notes (Box 89)
  - Chromatic Fugue and Variations, McIntosh, Angus (Box 89)
  - Meanings of Meaning, Kinds of Signs (Box 89)
  - Miscellaneous linguistic and semantic notes resulting from early stages of Pawnee paper (Box 89)
  - Systems of Consanguinity and Affinity of the Human Family, Morgan, Lewis Henry, 1818-1881 (Box 89)
  - Motor and Sensory Homunculi (Box 89)
  - Personality (Box 89)
  - Petrov (Box 89)
  - Ph.D. Diploma, 1949 (Box OS)
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
    Oversized.
  - Phonemics (Box 89)
  - Phonetics, 2.0 folders (Box 89)
  - Phonetics and Phonemics: Outline for Summer, 1954 (Box 89)
  - Phonetics Charts (Box 89)
  - Pitch: English (Box 89)
  - Positional Analysis of Syntax - German and Chinese (Box 89)
  - Projected Papers - Miscellaneous (Box 89)
  - Projected Papers - Oneida Text (Box 89)
  - Projected Papers - Syntax (Box 89)
  - Report for Differential Geometry (Box 90)
  - Semantics (Box 90)
  - Shanghai (Box 90)
  - [Sheet Music] (Box 91)
    General note
    Located at end of series.
    Music for guitar and ukuelele. Includes such classics as: Dinah Shore: Favorite Songs; "The Letter That Never Came" featured by Sunny Joe and Rhubarb Red; "The Preacher and the Bear" featured by Doc Hopkins; "The Bright Mohawk Valley" featured by Sunny Boy Marcus; "The Broncho Buster" featured by Ken Houchins; "Sing Again that Sweet Refrain" featured by Ozzie Nelson and His Orchestra; "I'd Like to be in Texas when They Round Up in the Spring" featured by Tex Fletcher; "The Last Great Round Up" featured by Annie, Judy, and Zeke; "Heaven Heaven" featured by Jane Harvey; "The Written Letter" featured by Russ Perkins; "She was Happy 'Til She Met You" by Charles Graham and Monroe Rosenfeld.
  - Sign and Symbol (Box 90)
  - [Social Statistics] (Box 90)
  - Sociology 140, 2.0 folders (Box 90)
  - Statistics, 2.0 folders (Box 90)
  - Steffre. Apurar (Box 90)
  - Lab A - Sociology 132, Stillman, Robert (Box 90)
  - Structural Semantics (Box 90)
  - Structural Semantics - Korean and Japanese (Box 90)
  - Structural Semantics - Outline. Partly from U. Michigan, Summer 1966 (Box 90)
  - Student Notes and Assignments (Box 90)
  - Suggested Readings...for Ph.D. degree in Sociology and Anthropology (Box 90)
  - Lexico-statistics, Swadesh, Morris, 1909-1967 (Box 90)
  - Method for Phonetic Accuracy and Speed, Swadesh, Morris, 1909-1967 (Box 90)
  - Teaching files from Yale Courses, n.d.; 1.0 box (Box 92)
    Box of index cards located at end of series.
  - [Teaching Notebooks], 9.0 vol. (Box 91)
    Includes scheduling notes, lecture notes and outlines, etc. Occasionally offers insight to Lounsbury's personal interests. For instance, one page contains instructions for square-dancing.
  - Theories on Signs and Notes on Sapir (Box 91)
  - Tree of Jesse. Wadsworth Athenaeum (Box 91)
  - Vocabulary Lists (Box 91)
  - The Theory of Signs (Bibliography), Wells, Rulon (Box 91)
  - Whorf, Benjamin Lee (Box 91)
  - Word Lists (Box 91)
  - Writing (Box 91)
  - Writing Systems - Barthel, Thomas S. Easter Island (Box 91)
  - Writing Systems - History, Introductory Notes (Box 91)
  - Writing Systems - Miscellaneous Alphabets (Box 91)
  - Yale Graduate School Coursework, 2.0 folders (Box 91)
- Series IV. Computer Research (Box 93-95)
  - Addresses (Box 93)
  - Alphabetization (Box 93)
  - Bibliography (Box 93)
  - [Calculating Moon-age Corrections ... in Maya eclipse table of the Dresden Codex] (Box 93)
  - Computer Information (Box 93)
  - Data Files - Journal and Tax Accounting (Box 93)
  - Data Notebooks, 2.0 vol. (Box 93)
  - Diskettes, 1.0 box (Box 95)
    Contains 5.25 inch, 3.5 inch, and zip disks.
  - Disk-File Directories (Box 93)
  - Forth (Box 93)
  - General Programming Files (Box 93)
  - Generating Oneida Verb Forms (Box 93)
  - Mayacal (Box 93)
  - Miscellaneous Accounting (Box 93)
  - Miscellaneous Program Notes (Box 93)
  - Miscellaneous Programming: Operations, Dioph., Primes, Tanjii, TXPRO, CMDUG (Box 93)
  - Oneida.Elm File (Box 94)
  - Oneida Verb Programming (Box 94)
  - Sinott. "Planets" (Box 94)
  - Text-processing Program (Box 94)
  - Tracings 150-156. "Align" (Box 94)
  - Tuscarora Programming, 2.0 folders (Box 94)
  - WordStar Information, References (Box 94)
- Series V. Recommendations and Evaluations, 2.0 lin. feet (Box 96-99)
  Conditions Governing Access note
  Restricted.
- Series VI. Card Files, 129.0 box (Box 100-228)
  - Ancash, 11.0 box (Box 100-110)
  - Ancash / Quechua 3, 2.0 box (Box 111-112)
  - Aymara, 10.0 box (Box 113-122)
  - Aymara Suffixes, 1.0 box (Box 123)
  - Bororo, 2.0 box (Box 124-125)
  - Cuzco, 9.0 box (Box 126-134)
  - Cuzco Quechua, 3.0 box (Box 135-137)
  - Iroquoian, 47.0 box (Box 138-184)
    - Cayuga, 1.0 box (Box 138)
    - Cherokee, 1.0 box (Box 139)
    - Cherokee Data Files, 10.0 box (Box 140-149)
    - Cherokee Lexicon, 2.0 box (Box 150-151)
    - Miscellaneous Iroquois, 1.0 box (Box 152)
    - Mohawk, 9.0 box (Box 153-161)
    - Oneida, 14.0 box (Box 162-175)
    - Onondaga I, 1.0 box (Box 176)
    - Onondaga II / Seneca, 1.0 box (Box 177)
    - Seneca, 4.0 box (Box 178-181)
    - Tuscarora, 3.0 box (Box 182-184)
  - Quechua, 1.0 box (Box 185)
  - Shanghai, 10.0 box (Box 186-195)
  - Shanghai Finals, 5.0 box (Box 196-200)
  - Shanghai Tones, 5.0 box (Box 201-205)
  - South America, 2.0 box (Box 206-207)
  - South America Language Data Files - Terena, 3.0 box (Box 208-210)
  - South America Language Data Files - Terena and Other, 3.0 box (Box 211-213)
  - South American Vocabulary, 2.0 box (Box 214-215)
  - Terena, 9.0 box (Box 216-224)
  - Unidentified, 1.0 box (Box 225)
  - Yunga / German, 3.0 box (Box 226-228)
- Series VII. Audio Materials (Box 229-240)
  Many analog recordings have been converted to digital files. Some recordings exist as Digital Audio Tape (DAT), WAV files, and MP3 files. Links to digital files in the finding aid are for in-house use only.
  - Analog Recordings
    Physical objects.
    - Cherokee, n.d.; 2 cass.
      Willard Walker, Conversational Cherokee, chapters 2-10; 7 Cherokee stories; Cherokee letter.
    - Foster, Michael, and Hanni Woodbury, 1995; 7 cass.
      Interview of FGL.
    - Iroquois, General, 1956; 1 5" reel
      "White Dog ceremony, David Thomas, et al."
    - Lounsbury, Floyd G., n.d.; 11 5" reels, 1 7" reel
      Lectures and dictation re kinship (7 reels), complementary descent (1 reel), culture (1 reel), glyph terminology (1 reel), paper on language and philosophy (1 reel).
    - Cayuga (possibly), n.d.; 1 3" reel
      "Thanksgiving: Address of Exhortation on behalf of the Chiefs (Dubbed from disc recordings made in Brantford)."
    - Maliseet, 1978; 1 5" reel
      Stories recorded by David Sherwood at Tobique, New Brunswick, consultant was Lorraine Francis.
    - Mohawk, 1989; 1 cass.
      "The Mohawks Learn Mohawk."
    - Oneida, 1971, 1984, n.d.; 8 5" reels, 7 cass.
      Recordings of various materials (addresses, Tekanawitah, etc.) given by Demas Elm, Ray Elm, Bruce Elijah, and Venus Walker.
    - Quechua, n.d.; 3 5" reels
      "Quechua: Malikaca" (2 tapes), "Quechua: Aysokuna, sent. 1-7. (practice tape)" (1 tape).
    - Stray Numbers, 1957, 1959; 1 5" reel
      Copied from William C. Sturtevant's "Stray Number Series tapes: Mikasuki Seminole, Creek, Catawba.
    - Tuscarora, 1980, 1991, n.d.; 4 cass., 1 5" reel
      Gospel recordings, narrations, vocabulary, unspecified. Shelved with recordings.
    - Unidentified, n.d.; 1 5" reel, 2 cass.
      "J. Williams: Sor, 20 Estudios", "J. Aldano: Carcasse, St. C."; "Yotinuhsote'" (2 cass.).
    - Wyandot, 1968; 1 5" reel
      "Dr. Marius Barbeau reading a Wyandot narrative."
    - Yucatan, n.d.
      "Yucatan: Teabo-Miller, Krebs".
    - Zuni (?), n.d.; 1 5" reel
      "Dennis Tedlock, Practice Tape: Zuni?"
    - Abenaki, n.d.; 1 7" reel
      "Abenaki ks, G[ordon] Day". Contents unspecified.
    - Bororo, n.d.; 2 7" reels
      Contents unspecified.
    - Cayuga, 1960, n.d.; 2 7" reels
      Recordings of H. Skye and Mrs. Greene. Contents unspecified.
    - Cherokee, n.d.; 4 7" reels
      Bushyhead and Cook Cherokee Lessons.
    - Guarani and Terena, 1 7" reel
    - Mohawk, n.d.; 3 7" reels
    - Oneida, n.d.; 2 7" reels
      "Transcriptions of Oneida I, II, III from wire"; "Oneida practice tape."
    - Onondaga, 1950; 8 7" reels
      Texts and translations, including Condolence Ceremony-list of contents included.
    - Panama, n.d.; 2 7" reels
      Language(s) and contents unspecified.
    - Quechua, n.d.; 2 7" reels
      "Quechua: Junius Bird's group"; "Quechua dictation FGL: Dictation for phonology and for analysis of text of Malikace."
    - Seneca, 1952-1953, n.d.; 3 7" reels
      Seneca songs, one reel labeled "dubbed from wire."
    - Tuscarora, n.d.; 2 7" reels
    - Umotina, n.d.; 1 7" reel
      "Umatina spool I, cont ca. 10 min." Contents unspecified.
    - Uncompaghre Ute, n.d.; 1 7" reel
      "Harriet Johnson, 45, White River-Uncompaghre Ute, Whiterocks, Utah." Contents unspecified.
    - Winnebago, n.d.; 1 7" reel
      "Winnebago song."
    - Yucatec, 1963; 1 7" reel
      Recorded in Merida by Brendt Berlin, William C. Sturtevant, and Charles O. Frake.
    - Bakaire, n.d.; wire-2 spools
      Words, phrases, stories, etc.
    - Bororo, n.d.; wire-3 spools
    - Cayuga, n.d.; wire-1 wire spool
      1/2 hour recording of Alec General.
    - Cherokee, n.d.; wire-1 spool
    - Guarani and Terena, wire-1 spool
      Texts identified in Portuguese.
    - Guarani, n.d.; 10" records-7
      Musica tipica paraguaya. Includes transcription of "Tetagua Sapucai (Grito del Pueblo)."
    - Micmac, n.d.; wire-1 spool
      "Micmac-Barney Peters." Contents unspecified.
    - Mohawk, 1951-1952; wire-8 spools
    - Oneida, n.d.; wire-4 spools
    - Paressi, n.d.; wire-1 spool
    - Quechua, n.d.; wire-2 spools
      Contents unspecified. One spool labeled "Quechua," the other "Qu. Syn."
    - Bororo, n.d.; 12" record-1
      Contents not specified.
    - Cayuga, n.d.; 12" records-3
    - Cayuga (?), n.d.; 12" records-4
      Condolence Ceremony chanted by George Thomas. One record jacket labeled "Fenton recording of Condolence."
    - Seneca, n.d.; wire-1 spool
    - Oneida, n.d.; 12" records-5
    - Oneida, 1950; 12" records-6
      "Dekanawidah" as told by Damas Elm.
    - Quechua, n.d.; 12" records-6
    - Terena, n.d.; wire-1 spool
      One spool has Portuguese label "Lessons in Terena," the other "Terena and Guarani, contents unspecified.
    - Terena, n.d.; 12" record-1
    - Tuscarora, n.d.; 12" records-2
    - Unidentified, n.d.; 12" record-1